Sanford, Donn mss., 1961-2002 LMC 2826
Lilly Library
Sanford, Donn mss.
1961-2002
Lilly Library
Sanford, Donn W., 1940-2004
Miniature Book Society
LMC 2826
3 Boxes
The Sanford, Donn mss., 1961-2002, consist of correspondence, records, and memorabilia relating to the Miniature Book Society and Sanford's involvement in the organization.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 2013
Biographical Note
Donn W. Sanford, 1940-2004, was a writer, publisher, reporter, and founder of the Sanford Organization with a passion for miniature books. Sanford served as President of the Miniature Book Society from 1999-2001 as well as editor of the MBS newsletter, receiving the Glasgow Cup Award from the Society and organizing one of their annual conclaves.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, printed materials, and memorabilia relating to the Conclave organized by Sanford. Also included are meeting minutes, organizational records, miniature books and newspaper articles, and photographs relating to the Miniature Book Society and miniature book trade. Materials relating to Kathryn Richard and Ward Schori complete the collection. Collection includes instructions on the miniature book making process, miniature books in the mainstream media, and a bibliography of miniature book literature. Other materials include a set of VHS tapes, a floppy disk, and a magazine about miniature bookmaking. Also included is a sampling of a miniature bookmaking toolkit. The collection of miniature books included in this collection have been filed separately.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by series, including Miniature Book Society Materials, Publishing, Correspondence, Miscellaneous, Photos, and A/V Materials.
Related Materials
See Miniature Book Society mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Miniature books --Societies.
- Miniature Book Society Materials
  - Documents pertaining to Conclave XI of the Miniature Book Society; has to do with Grand Conclave meeting/conference in Chicago, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Document in binder that contains ad directory of Conclave XI's members and has other planning materials for the Grand Conclave, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Materials from Conclave VII, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Commemorative bookmark, miniature books, notes and personal correspondence, newsletter, auction listing, and memorial items for deceased Society member from Conclave XIII in Pasadena; also includes commemorative miniature books from other conclaves, 1995-2004 (Box 1)
  - Accommodation information, auction listing, brochure and commemorative miniature books from Conclave XIV in San Francisco, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Auction listings, registration forms, list of online resources for miniature books, list of exhibitors items of correspondence, nametag, magnifier, and commemorative miniature books for Conclave XVI in Charleston, South Carolina, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets, fliers, vendor materials, and photographs from the 1999 Conclave XVII in Koblentz, Germany (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets and directories for Conclave XVIII of the Miniature Book Society in Vermont, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Directories, miniature books from conclave, Lilly Library brochure, program, and pamphlets from Conclave XIX in Indianapolis/Bloomington, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Tourism brochures for following year's conclave in Toronto, directories, membership form, and conclave schedule for Conclave XX in Covington, Kentucky, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Directories, auction listings, program, nametag, meeting minutes, and budget from Conclave XXI in Toronto, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Directories and updated lists of miniature book publishers, sellers, and binders associated with Miniature Book Society from the 1983 conclave (Box 1)
  - Member listing, auction listing, publisher's listing, nametag, and commemorative miniature books from 1997 conclave in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies and Book Lists
- Publishing Materials
  - Announcements 1 (Box 1)
  - Announcements 2 (Box 1)
  - Announcements 3 (Box 1)
  - Announcements 4 (Box 1)
  - "Yodelings" Newsletter and Publishing Announcements (Box 1)
  - Articles and Drafts, Schori, Ward (Box 1)
  - Press of Schori Ward (1/2) (Box 1)
  - Press of Schori Ward (2/2) (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Amistad Press, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Frank, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Babcock, Ralph, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Bachrach, Lilyan, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Bahar, Ann, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Barris, Bob, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Brady, Don, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Curran, Rev. Joseph L., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Dawson, Glen, 1993
  - Doncaster, William, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Doolittle, Jim, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Ed, J., 1999-2002 (Box 2)
  - Edison, Julian, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Falter, Michael, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Fleming, Dick, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Gellatly, Peter, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Gurney, Roy, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Helbert, Clifford, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Jacobs, Alden, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Janssen, Philip, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Jeggle, 1992 (Box 2)
  - John, Betty, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Kal, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Kellet, Jan, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Lathourakis, John P., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Lariviere, John, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Marcus Stanley, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Markov, 1993 (Box 2)
  - McDonald, Ian, 1992 (Box 2)
  - McGehee, Caroline, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Pechtovik, Pavel, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Poska, Val, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Rickard, Kathryn, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Ritchie, Ward, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Schori, Ward, 1990-1993 (Box 2)
  - Thurkow, Guus, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Winterstein, Jrene, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Weber, Francis. J. (Writings included), 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1994-2002 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Bookman's Weekly (Box 2)
  - Miniature Book Society Materials (Box 2)
  - Military Documents (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles (1/2) (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles (2/2) (Box 2)
  - Various (Box 2)
- Photos
  - Album 1 (Box 2)
  - Album 2 (Box 2)
- A/V Material
  - Mosaic Press: Binding Miniature Books (Box 2)
  - ABC News: Miniature Books (Box 2)
  - Children's Books: Miniature Books (Box 2)
  - Miniature Book Collecting (Francis J. Weber ABC News) (Box 2)
  - Children's Books: Miniature Books (Box 2)
  - Untitled VHS (Box 2)
  - KABC-TV Miniature Books (Box 2)